Kritika Tanwar

Email address: kritikatanwar13@gmail.com
Phone number: (+91) 8600444871

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kritika-tanwar

ABOUT ME

I use design to transform the world from the imagination to the actual. On my project designs, I constantly strive to create significant concept experiences in order to better understand the demands of the organization goals and achieve business objectives.

EDUCATION AND TRAININGS

UX and Interaction Design Training

OCT 2021 - DEC 2021

Coditas Solutions LLP, Pune, India

Project Title: Mobile application design to engage blood donors in India

Relevant course work: User research, Design thinking, Interaction design, Information architecture, Visual design, Usability testing, Wireframing & Prototyping, Color theory, Typography, Design system

Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics and Telecomm. Engineering)

AUG 2012 - JUL 2016

Savitribai Phule Pune University (formerly University of Pune), Pune, India

Thesis Title: Home automation using Raspberry Pi.

Relevant course work: Object Oriented Programming, Micro-controllers and application, electronic product design, Embedded systems & RTOS.

Committees & clubs: Ore team member of the college festival

- Treasurer of IEEE student branch of I2IT, Pune Section, Region 10
- Winner of Badminton Doubles competition for three years in a row.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance UI Designer

APR 2021 - DEC 2021

Foces Staffing Private Limited, Pune, India

- Gathered and evaluated user requirements, in collaboration with the product manager.
- Designed graphic user interface elements, like menus, tabs, and landing pages.
- Created UI mockups and prototypes based on user requirements.

Software Engineer APR 2018 - OCT 2021

Tech Mahindra Ltd., Pune, India

- $\,^\circ\,$ Conducted user research and testing.
- Developed wireframes and task flows based on user needs.
- Collaborated with designers and developers to create intuitive, user-friendly software.
- Communicated design ideas and prototypes to developers.

Associate Software Engineer

OCT 2016 - APR 2018

Tech Mahindra Ltd., Pune, India

- $\,^\circ\,$ Designed test plans, scenarios, scripts, and procedures.
- Executed tests on source code.
- Analyzed test results and reporting to the development team.
- $\,^\circ$ Collaborated with the development team to correct bugs and errors.

CERTIFICATIONS

Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Prototypes
Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate

JUN 2021 MAY 2021

Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ide Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design

MAR 2021

Issuing Organization: Coursera, Google

Graphic Design Elements for Non-Designers Specialization

Issuing Organization: Coursera, University of Colorado Boulder

AUG 2020

PROJECTS

Blood donation Mobile Application - "DigiBlood"

OCT 2021 - DEC 2021

App to engage blood donors in India

Improving WhatsApp Case Study

SEPT 2021 - OCT 2021

Examined the current UX of WhatsApp using user feedback and competitive research data, updated and added new features to make the platform more user-friendly and reduce existing user issues.

Heuristic Evaluation - Cred Mobile Application

OCT 2021 - NOV 2021

Heuristic assessment for Cred Application. Analyzed all 10 heuristic principles on the applications and noted down the issues and recommendations.

Split Sharing Mobile App

FEB 2021 - JUL 2021

GoSplit is a concept project app, to make the splitting of bills easier and faster.

CREATIVE WORKS

Digital artistAUG 2019 – PRESENT

Owner of Instagram business account 'Kritika.tanwar' launched in Aug 2019.

Providing digital services (e-invites, custom illustrations, graphic design) and products (calendar, stickers). Launched my first product 'Calendar 2021' in Oct 2020, with a sticker collection.

Product Link: https://www.behance.net/gallery/117721643/Calendar-2021

Instagarm account link: https://www.instagram.com/kritika.tanwar/

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Bravo Award Awarding institution: Tech Mahindra Ltd.

JUN 2019

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Sketching

• Badminton

Painting

Exploring other cultures

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Hindi (Mother tongue)
- English, Marathi (Native)